Guide to the Consumer Reports Books records, 1938-1995 RL.11864
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports Books records
1938-1995
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11864
6.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Consumer Reports Books is responsible for publishing buyers' guides and other subject-based books relating to consumer education and public interest issues. The Consumer Reports Books records include catalogs of offerings; correspondence relating to various publications; requests for reprints; drafts of book projects and other printed materials. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Administrative Files; Correspondence; Directors and Editors Files; The Medicine Show
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Consumer Reports Books is responsible for publishing buyers' guides and other subject-based books relating to consumer education and public interest issues.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports Books records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related material may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Editorial Department records
Collection Overview
The Consumer Reports Books records include catalogs of offerings; correspondence relating to various publications; requests for reprints; drafts of book projects and other printed materials.
Consumer education; Consumer advocacy; consumer protection; Book industries and trade; Book editors -- United States -- Correspondence; Publishers and publishing; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- General Administrative Files, 1938-1995; 1
  - Bibliophile newsletter, 1987-1989 (Box 1)
  - Business plan (Christopher Kuppig), 1990 (Box 1)
  - Catalogs, 1986-1993; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Catalogs--Distribution lists, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Catalogs--St. Martin's/Griffin, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Reviews of Consumers Union books, 1938-1989; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1939-1982; 2
  - Automobile insurance, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Education: Its New Look, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Education for Low-Income Families, 1964-1969; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Consumer Education for Low-Income Families, 1964-1969 (Box 2)
  - Consumer Education in Lincoln High School, 1965-1969 (Box 2)
  - Consumer protection, 1966-1968 (Box 2)
  - Dark Side of the Marketplace, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
  - Defending the Environment, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
  - Family planning, 1949-1975; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Funerals and burials, 1963-1975 (Box 2)
  - Good Health and Bad Medicine, 1939-1951 (Box 2)
  - Great American Motion Sickness, 1971 (Box 2)
  - Health Guide for Travelers, 1956-1973; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Health Guide for Travelers, 1956-1973 (Box 12)
  - Injury Industry, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
  - Insurance and Your Security, 1948-1955 (Box 3)
  - Intelligent Buyer's Guide to Sellers, 1965-1969 (Box 3)
  - Licit and Illicit Drugs, 1969-1976; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Life insurance, 1967-1974; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Life insurance, 1967-1974 (Box 12)
  - Love, Sex and Aging, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Medical Messiahs, 1968-1969 (Box 3)
  - Medicine and Health, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Medicine Show, 1961-1975; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Movies for television, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
  - Overweight, 1969-1974 (Box 4)
  - Passenger Car Design and Highway Safety, 1962-1969 (Box 4)
  - Photographic Buyer's Handbook, 1939-1950 (Box 4)
  - Real Voice, 1964-1968 (Box 4)
  - Silent Spring, 1962-1970; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Since Silent Spring, 1970-1971 (Box 4)
  - Small Car in Your Family, 1959-1964 (Box 4)
  - Smoking and the Public Interest, 1963; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Smoking and the Public Interest, 1963 (Box 12)
  - Smoking and the Public Interest, 1963-1965; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Weights and Measures and the Consumer, 1966-1971 (Box 5)
  - Wine and spirits, 1961-1973 (Box 5)
- Directors and Editors Files, 1958-1982; 3
  - Irwin Landau, 1982; 1
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 5)
  - Jonathan Leff, 1958-1975; 2
    - Biographical sketch, 1975 (Box 5)
    - Cancer: An Environmental Disease, 1975; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Consumers in Trouble (David Caplovitz), 1974; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Consumers in Trouble (David Caplovitz), 1974 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1975; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Manuscripts not used, 1970-1975 (Box 6)
    - Permissions and requests to reprint, 1963-1971; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Permissions and requests to reprint, 1968-1973; 6 folders (Box 7)
    - Special Publications Committee, 1965 (Box 7)
    - Testimony on narcotics legislation, 1973 (Box 7)
- The Medicine Show, Revised Edition, 1974; 4
  - Preface and Introduction, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Chapter 1-Chapter 10, manuscripts and source material, 1974; 14 folders (Box 8)
  - Chapter 11-Chapter 18, manuscripts and source material, 1974; 12 folders (Box 9)
  - Chapter 19-Chapter 25, manuscripts and source material, 1974; 9 folders (Box 10)
  - Chapter 25-Chapter 32, manuscripts and source material, 1974; 10 folders (Box 11)
  - Glossary and index, 1974; 3 folders (Box 11)